# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I'll share with you an everyday dish
# 苦瓜酿肉
Bitter Gourd Stuffed Meat
# 首先我们准备碧绿色的苦瓜两条
First, prepare two green bitter gourds
# 将苦瓜切头去尾
Remove the two ends
# 因为苦瓜两头比较狭小无法酿肉所以必须去除
Since the ends are too narrow to stuff the meat in, we need to remove them
# 然后将苦瓜切成1厘米左右的节备用
Then cut the bitter gourd to chunks that are 1cm thick
# 切好节之后用手将苦瓜中的籽去掉
After cutting, remove the seeds by hand
# 苦瓜中白色的瓜瓤部分带有苦涩味
The white portion is bitter
# “怕吃苦”的同学可以用小刀将其全部去除干净
If you don't like the bitter tast, use a knife to remove it all
# 下一步我们开始准备苦瓜的初步处理
Then we start preprocessing the bitter gourd
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First add some water to the wok
# 然后加入食用盐1大勺（约3克）
Then add a large spoon of salt (around 3g)
# 加盐的目的是防止营养流失
Adding salt keeps the nutrition
# 大火将水烧开之后再加入适量的食用油
Add some oil after the water boils
# 然后将切好的苦瓜下锅焯水1分钟
Then add the cutted bitter gourd and parboil for a minute
# 加油焯水的目的是保持苦瓜成菜之后的光泽
Parboiling with oil keeps the glaze of the bitter gourd
# 还有一点就是防止苦瓜发黄
And prevents it from turning yellow
# 1分钟之后将苦瓜捞出放入冷水中浸泡
After one minute, take the bitter gourd out and place it in cold water
# 待苦瓜凉透之后捞出沥干水份备用
When it's completely cooled down, remove the water and set aside
# 下一步开始准备猪肉
Next, start preparing the pork
# 准备半肥瘦的五花肉1小块
Prepare a small piece of 50% lean 50% fat pork
# 去掉猪皮之后先切成片
Remove the skin and slice it
# 然后再剁成肉泥备用
Then cut it to grounded meat
# 下一步开始调味
Then start marinating the meat
# 碗中加入食用盐1勺
Add a spoon of salt to the bowl
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a little ground pepper
# 加入生抽酱油3克
Add 3g of soy sauce
# 加入少许老抽调底色
Add some dark soy sauce for the color
# 然后将猪肉搅拌均匀
Then mix the meat with the sauces
# 这一步的目的是上劲
This allows the meat to come together
# 猪肉上劲之后再加入1个鸡蛋搅拌均匀
Then add an egg and mix properly
# 最后再加入少许玉米淀粉拌匀备用
Finally add some corn starch to mix and set aside
# 下一步开始制作
Then start cooking
# 首先我们在苦瓜圈中抹上干淀粉
First, apply some starch to the inner side of the ring-shaped bitter gourds
# 这一步的目的是让肉泥粘的更稳
This is to allow the ground meat to stay in the ring
# 然后将调好味的肉泥酿入苦瓜中
Then add the marinated meat to the bitter gourds
# 同学们可以尽量的多加一些肉末
More meat is better
# 这样能够使苦瓜更加的饱满
Because it makes the final product more rich
# 然后在酿好的肉末两边粘上干淀粉备用
Then apply starch on the two sides of the meat
# 粘干淀粉的目的是防止两面煎的时候粘连
Starch prevents the two sides from sticking together when it's fried
# 下一步我们开始调碗汁
Next, we start to prepare the sauce
# 碗中加入生抽酱油5克
Add 5g of soy sauce to the bowl
# 加入蚝油3克
Add 3g of oyster sauce
# 加入少许白糖
Add a little sugar
# 加入食用盐1勺
Add a spoon of salt
# 加入清汤40克
Add 40g of clear broth
# 最后加入适量的干淀粉（土豆淀粉）搅拌均匀备用
Finally add some potato starch and mix it properly
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start pan-frying
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
When the wok is heated, add some oil to the wok
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
Then pour the oil out
# 然后加入少许的底油
Now add some base oil
# 油温4成热之后依次下入苦瓜
When it's 40% heated, add the bitter gourds one by one
# 然后开小火煎8分钟
Then turn to low heat for 8 minutes
# 同学们切记必须小火慢慢煎
Keep in mind we need low heat
# 不能开大火否则很容易煎糊
Because high heat easily burns the bitter gourds
# 正所谓慢工出细活
Patience is the best practice
# 中途用筷子将其翻面煎香
Midway, flip the bitter gourds to pan-fry the other side
# 两面煎香之后转中火然后缓缓加入调好的碗汁
When both sides are ready, turn to mid heat and slowly pour in the prepared sauce
# 碗汁下锅之后转中小火
Then turn to mid-low heat
# 将汤汁收浓即可出锅装盘
When the sauce becomes condensed, it's ready to be served
# 一道非常美味的“生活菜”苦瓜酿肉就制作完成
Now a delicious everyday dish, Bitter Gourd Stuffed Meat, is ready
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一：必须选择绿色结实的苦瓜，这样成菜更绿
# 第二：焯水的时候加油、盐的目的是让苦瓜保持翠绿，同时也能够去除一些苦涩味
# 第三：煎制的时候必须小火慢慢煎，否则中间不容易熟
# 第四：最后收汁不能超过3分钟，否则成菜容易发黄
# 苦瓜酿肉的技术总结完毕
Now let's summarize the techniques
Firstly, we need to choose green and riped bitter gourds so that the product looks bright-colored
Secondly, we need to add oil and salt while parboiling to keep the bitter gourds green and remove its bitterness
Thirdly, we need to turn to low heat while pan-frying or the middle part would stay rare
Fourthly, don't boil the sauce for more than 3 minutes, or the bitter gourds would turn yellow
Above are all the techniques